<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/siegman/Documents/Shahar/years/y2021/t_and_t/grobid-server/grobid-0.6.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Negotiation policies and coalition tools in e-marketplace environment</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2010-07-14">14 July 2010</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paolo</forename><surname>Renna</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">DIFA</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Basilicata</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Via dell&apos;Ateneo Lucano, 10</addrLine>
									<postCode>85100</postCode>
									<settlement>Potenza</settlement>
									<country key="IT">Italy</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Negotiation policies and coalition tools in e-marketplace environment</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2010-07-14">14 July 2010</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cie.2010.07.007</idno>
					<note type="submission">Received 12 February 2009 Received in revised form 7 July 2010 Accepted 8 July 2010</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2021-02-02T11:56+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>Multi Agent Systems Negotiation E-marketplace Discrete-event simulation Coalition</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>The e-marketplace in Business To Business applications allows enterprises to make economic transactions in a virtual marketplace. Often Small and Medium Enterprises (SMEs) do not participate to this potential opportunity because of some distrust as: the benefits of e-marketplace participation are not perceived clearly; SMEs doubt that e-marketplace fits the products offered. The possibility to evaluate the real value added by an e-marketplace can be a driving force to adopting e-marketplace for SMEs. The research proposes negotiation policies, customer&apos;s tactics and coalition tools as a value added services in e-marketplaces. The e-marketplace scenario is a private neutral linear owned by a third part with catalogue based procurement actions. A Multi Agent System methodology is used to implement the architecture of the e-marketplace. Furthermore, the author proposes the use of discreteevent simulation to test the suggested methodologies and to evaluate the economic value of adopting the proposed negotiation and coalition tools in e-marketplaces. The simulations are conducted in a very dynamic environment and a proper statistical analysis is performed. The simulation results show that the proposed methodologies lead to benefits both for suppliers and customers.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
